<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Personal &#8211; Neil Wilcoxson</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>CS Student and non-Professional Photographer</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 19:39:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Credit Card Frustrations (for people under 21)</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/09/22/credit-card-frustrations-for-people-under-21/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 21:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bank accounts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discover card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secured credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unsecured credit card]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a lot of advice about credit cards out there.  While I could give the same advice all over again, I want to cover [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is a lot of advice about credit cards out there.  While I could give the same advice all over again, I want to cover a different issue that I haven’t seen covered nearly as much, getting a credit card as an under 21 college student.  The thing is, most of the people giving advice are making assumptions that aren’t true.  They are either assuming that, A, things are the same as when they were this age, or B, they are assuming that age couldn’t possibly have anything to do with it.  In this post, I’ll tell you about the barriers that I’ve run into, and what I’m doing to get around them.</p>
<p>First, let’s cover this story that every old person tells you about credit cards in college.  They say that there are going credit card issuers all over campus giving you free stuff to sign up for their credit card.  I saw nothing like this, and it turns out that I shouldn’t have, because in 2009 the CARD act was put into place with a whole load of restrictions on how credit card issuers do business with people under 21.  While I’m not a huge fan of people trying to sell me stuff while I’m walking to class, I am incredibly frustrated at how hard this has made it to get a credit card.</p>
<p>Now let’s answer the question as to whether I actually need a credit card.  If the idea behind this law is to prevent young people from making stupid decisions, could I be making one by trying to get a credit card?  People tend to jump to the conclusion that an eighteen year old would only want to use a credit card to buy things that he can’t afford.  I can come up with four other reasons why a credit card is useful that do not involve incurring interest penalties.</p>
<p>1. Credit Building</p>
<p>This was the main motivating factor for me.  While I do not need to borrow money now, my credit report will have a huge impact on the interest rate of any money I borrow in the future.  Additionally, credit reports are used for many things other than borrowing money.  Potential employers and landlords often use this in their decision making process.</p>
<p>2. Insurance/Purchase Protection</p>
<p>Young people buy stuff that can benefit from this too.</p>
<p>3. To help with cash flow</p>
<p>I don’t want to suggest that it is a good thing to regularly rely on credit cards for emergencies.  I like the idea of having an emergency fund.  However, I like to keep mine in an online savings account.  If something comes up that exceeds the amount in my checking account, I can’t just put it on my debit card.  In this situation, having the credit card buys me the two or three days I need for the bank transfer to go through.</p>
<p>4. Cashback</p>
<p>I will admit that at this point my expenses are pretty low, and thus the dollar value of these rewards isn’t very high for me.  However, every place that accepts a credit card has the extra credit card fees built into the price, so it seems silly to throw this away by paying cash.</p>
<p>Now that I’ve established that a young person could want a credit card for responsible reasons, let’s talk about my struggle in getting one.  I didn’t really know where to begin, so I tried to follow what little advice I had.  I had heard it is easier to get approved for a card from a bank you have an account with.  So I applied (the particular bank doesn’t matter, because it’s the same situation across the board because of government regulation).  I got denied immediately, and a week later received a letter in the mail detailing why I had been denied.  Of course the letter listed the obvious reasons: length of accounts and number of accounts.  However, what got my attention was that they listed my credit score, which was in the high 700s.  To explain this I’ll have to give a few more details about my situation.  Before I went to college, my dad added me as an authorized user to one of his credit cards.  He gave me the card and I use it for things we have arranged ahead of time.  After getting my credit report for free online, I determined that the payments for this card were showing up on my credit report.  It should also be noted that the account opened date was before I was born, so that’s interesting.  The only other thing listed on my credit report was the inquiries I had made for several cards.</p>
<p>This is the thing that makes finding cards to apply for very difficult.  Every search tool out there bases what credit cards you should be eligible for one your credit score.  With a high 700’s, the tools claim I am eligible for almost anything, but when I apply to what are supposedly the easiest to get, I am denied.  This means that credit card companies are taking something else into account when they deny me.  I speculate that it could be one of two things.  One could be that they have other criteria for whether someone is approved.  Another might be that they don’t want to deal with the government regulations regarding giving credit cards to young people.</p>
<p>So what did I do about this?  Well, it was clearly that I couldn’t get any unsecured credit cards.  One of my banks actually suggested that I get their secured card.  I liked the idea, but their card charged an annual fee.  So I looked elsewhere.  I decided to get a Discover It Secured Card.  Before you go and sign up, make sure that you get some kind of bonus for doing this.  I unfortunately missed out on this.  Through their referral program, both people get $50, which ultimately gets doubled due to the first year double cashback bonus.  You can either find a friend who has a card and you would like to help out, or you can use my link: <a href="https://refer.discover.com/s/n4bmp">https://refer.discover.com/s/n4bmp</a>. The main reason why I chose the Discover card is because it does not charge an annual fee, and it can graduate to an unsecured card.  You also get some amount of cashback, although it isn’t as good as some of Discover’s other cards.  You also get to set the amount you put as deposit.  When deciding how much to put down, I had two theories in mind.  One was that the amount of I put down for the deposit would be how much I got as unsecured when the card graduated, so I wanted to put as much as possible.  On the other hand, I didn’t want to put too much and delay them from graduating my card because it was too risky.  I still don&#8217;t know for sure whether this card will graduate in a reasonable amount of time.</p>
<p>I’m sorry that I don’t have a solution.  It seems like this is one of those things that isn’t going to change any time soon.  It is incredibly frustrating to be told you’re an adult, but there are going to be a few exceptions until you get past 25.  Let me know how you feel in the comments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>More coming soon&#8230;</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/09/10/more-coming-soon/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 15:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=276</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve spent a few months hiding from my website, but I think it&#8217;s time to come back and get to work.  What I write is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve spent a few months hiding from my website, but I think it&#8217;s time to come back and get to work.  What I write is going to stay the same.  I will write things that I think need to be on the internet.  I will not write filler content just to stay on a schedule.</p>
<p>As for my personal life, I spent the summer with my family, as well as camping and hiking.  Here&#8217;s my brother and me at Zion National Park:</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-277" src="https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=860%2C574" alt="" width="860" height="574" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=1024%2C683 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=300%2C200 300w, https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=768%2C512 768w, https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?w=1720 1720w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Graduated High School: Now What?</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/06/14/graduated-high-school-now-what/index.html</link>
		<comments>./../../../2016/06/14/graduated-high-school-now-what/index.html#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 03:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=103</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After many long years, I have finally reached that point where I have no more of that “free” public education to attend.  At one point [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After many long years, I have finally reached that point where I have no more of that “free” public education to attend.  At one point in time, reaching this point was when an individual went and joined the workforce and became part of the “real world.”  However, I won’t be able to become part of the “real world” yet because I have to attend college.  For me there wasn’t really a choice in the matter.  In fact, over 95% of the people graduating from my high school are continuing on to a college education of some sort.  I also am the child of two highly educated parents who wouldn’t consider any option other than their child attending a four year university.  At this point a higher education seems like the best option for me, but it is entirely possible that I feel that way only because something said enough times becomes true.</p>
<p>While the primary focus of my life for the next four years may be set, there are a lot of other decisions I’ll be making.  To start, I have around eight weeks of summer vacation to use however I decide.  I’ll be using this first week to set some goals for myself.  I’ll definitely want to set goals in the broad categories fitness, career, and hobbies.  I’ll also have some other obvious things to take care of such as packing all of my belongings, and getting rid of the excess.</p>
<p>As I look over my classes for the fall, I see that I have a lot of my plate.  I’m told I’ll have to do a lot more studying than I’m used to.  Even on my busiest day, it looks like I’ll be spending less time in class than I did in high school.  I think I’ll like this better because less time will be wasted, which is all the additional time spent in high school really was.  Overall, I’m ready to go, but I’ll have to wait until August.  I’ll share more details when I have them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2016/06/14/graduated-high-school-now-what/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I Decided to Make a Website</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/05/29/why-i-decided-to-make-a-website/index.html</link>
		<comments>./../../../2016/05/29/why-i-decided-to-make-a-website/index.html#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 20:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=63</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Among many other reasons, the primary deciding factor in me launching my personal website was to expand my online presence.  To give credit, I was [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Among many other reasons, the primary deciding factor in me launching my personal website was to expand my online presence.  To give credit, I was really convinced of this being a necessity after reading Michael Price&#8217;s book: <em><a href="http://amzn.to/1RCXFC0">What Next? The Millennial&#8217;s Guide to Surviving and Thriving in the Real World</a> (affiliate link)</em>.  The book covers a variety of topics, but the one that impacted me the most was the importance of having a well developed online presence and how it will help you when starting your career.  Of course building an online presence takes time, so I can&#8217;t wait until I&#8217;ve graduated from college to start working on it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Another reason I launched my own website was to have more control over my content.  While social media has done a great job in giving everyone an online presence, it&#8217;s a little bit too uncertain for me to depend on it alone.  In the past I have had my Facebook account shutdown, and my Google AdSense account closed.  Having a website lowers the impact if something like that were to happen again.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Finally, there is another plus to starting my own website; It will be a good use of my time.  With my intended major of Computer Science, having put together a website is very relevant experience.  I know that running a website with a content management system (WordPress) may not seem like much, but a significant portion of the internet is run this way.  Additionaly, I may even get involved with some of the under the hood stuff.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m really looking forward to doing this, and I&#8217;ll be sure to share some more information about how exactly I got this thing up and running.  Until then I hope you&#8217;ll enjoy the rest of my site (not much at the moment), and my other work which I&#8217;ve linked to.  Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2016/05/29/why-i-decided-to-make-a-website/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
