<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Neil Wilcoxson</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description>CS Student and non-Professional Photographer</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 19:39:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>When will Bitcoin become less volatile?</title>
		<link>./../2017/11/05/when-will-bitcoin-become-less-volatile/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deflation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dollars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiat currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inflation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetary policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetary sytem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speculation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volatile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volatility]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The exchange rate for Bitcoin has been all over the place over the past few months, going as high as $7500 recently, and as low [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The exchange rate for Bitcoin has been all over the place over the past few months, going as high as $7500 recently, and as low as $3000 in September.  These price fluctuations are caused by speculation.  By speculation, I mean that people are buying it simply hoping that they will buy it now and then sell it later for a higher price.  I haven&#8217;t heard of many people exchanging their money for Bitcoin because it was necessary to go and buy some product or service that they wanted.  This leads to a circular problem.  Merchants don&#8217;t want to accept Bitcoin because it is so volatile.  On the other side of the coin, Bitcoin is volatile because most of its trading activity is done by people who are speculating on it.</p>
<p>There is a way to solve for this, but the first people to attempt it will see it as a huge risk.  The problem with Bitcoin is that merchants who accept want to charge the amount of Bitcoin that is precisely equivalent, at the time of the transaction, to the amount they would charge for the same item in dollars.  If someone wanted to use Bitcoin as their daily currency, a daily cup of coffee (or other item purchased regularly) would change in price everyday, by a lot.  Yes, some products, like gasoline, change in price on a daily basis, but not nearly to the extent that the Bitcoin exchange rate does.  Bitcoin will become much more viable when there are businesses that set a price in Bitcoin, not in the local government currency.  Ultimately this means that a business has to only accept Bitcoin, because if they offered both forms of payment, people would pick the one worth less at the time of the transaction.</p>
<p>Businesses take a loss when they decide to exchange their Bitcoin immediately at the time of the transaction.  However, this is necessary to cover expenses that must be paid in the government currency.  Perhaps taxes will always be paid in the government&#8217;s currency, but that doesn&#8217;t mean everything else has to be.  It would be difficult for a business to pay everyone else in Bitcoin.  If a business requires material goods, the others businesses providing those must be willing the accept Bitcoin.  Furthermore, employees have to be willing to accept Bitcoin.  For the employees to be willing to accept it, other businesses have to accept it.  Thus the cycle continues.</p>
<p>People are comfortable with dollars because they are confident that the paycheck they earn today will buy them the food they need tomorrow, the same way it did last week, and the weeks before that.  If we stopped comparing Bitcoin to the dollar, Bitcoin would also be able to provide this comfort.  In other words, Bitcoin will become less volatile when we start thinking about its value in terms of the goods and services it can buy, rather than how much of the government&#8217;s currency it can buy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will the Moto X (2015) Ever Get Updated?</title>
		<link>./../2017/10/29/will-the-moto-x-2015-ever-get-updated/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 13:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 6.0 Marshmallow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 7.0 Nougat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android security updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bootloader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lineage OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Pure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola bootloader unlock code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ROM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TWRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[updating Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warranty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have a Moto X Pure Edition which I bought at the end of last year as a last minute replacement to my LG G4, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a Moto X Pure Edition which I bought at the end of last year as a last minute replacement to my LG G4, which was poorly manufactured, and conveniently just out of warranty. Of the phones that were available to buy that day in Best Buy, the Moto X was the best option, but not necessarily a great option.</p>
<p>In my mind, Motorola had a reputation for keeping their phones up to date.  I had also heard that they made it easy to unlock your bootloader, even providing official instructions on how to do it.  Well, once you own one of their phones, your view on those things changes.  When I took the phone out of the box, it was on Android 5 Lollipop, but there was an update waiting, and I did that.  Now the phone was on Android 6 Marshmallow.  People kept posting online saying that the update to Android 7 Nougat was just around the corner.  To this day, that update has never arrived officially from Motorola.  And worse than that, the security patches are only up to December 2016.</p>
<p>Thinking that the update was just around the corner, I avoided unlocking the bootloader and installing Lineage OS (the replacement for CyanogenMod, which has had Android 7 available on the Moto X for a while now).  I would have just done it, but Motorola has a catch to providing the bootloader unlock code that people don&#8217;t tell you about, it voids the warranty.  Not just in the sense that they won&#8217;t fix anything stupid you do to the software under warranty, obtaining the code literally puts you in a database for no warranty work.  Given my bad experience with the LG G4 which failed by way of the same chipset that was in the Moto X, I wanted the warranty in force for as long as possible.  But recent Android security concerns changed my stance on this.  I went and got the unlock code and installed Lineage OS.  Even though they don&#8217;t offer a stable build yet, I&#8217;ve found it to have less bugs than the software that Motorola provided.</p>
<p>But wait, there&#8217;s more.  Whenever I start up the phone, it displays an obnoxious message about the bootloader being unlocked.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-315" src="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=860%2C574" alt="" width="860" height="574" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=1024%2C683 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=300%2C200 300w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=768%2C512 768w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>On the right is my Nexus 5 with a tasteful warning that the bootloader has been unlocked.  On the left is my Moto X telling you that using this device might injure people.  There is a way to replace this message with something else, but I think I&#8217;ll just leave it so I can have a good laugh at the expense of Motorola every time I restart my phone.</p>
<p>So the answer to the question: Will the Moto X ever get updated?  Officially no, but you can make it happen if you&#8217;re out of warranty or don&#8217;t mind voiding it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Credit Card Frustrations (for people under 21)</title>
		<link>./../2017/09/22/credit-card-frustrations-for-people-under-21/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 21:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bank accounts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[credit cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discover card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secured credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student credit card]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unsecured credit card]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a lot of advice about credit cards out there.  While I could give the same advice all over again, I want to cover [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is a lot of advice about credit cards out there.  While I could give the same advice all over again, I want to cover a different issue that I haven’t seen covered nearly as much, getting a credit card as an under 21 college student.  The thing is, most of the people giving advice are making assumptions that aren’t true.  They are either assuming that, A, things are the same as when they were this age, or B, they are assuming that age couldn’t possibly have anything to do with it.  In this post, I’ll tell you about the barriers that I’ve run into, and what I’m doing to get around them.</p>
<p>First, let’s cover this story that every old person tells you about credit cards in college.  They say that there are going credit card issuers all over campus giving you free stuff to sign up for their credit card.  I saw nothing like this, and it turns out that I shouldn’t have, because in 2009 the CARD act was put into place with a whole load of restrictions on how credit card issuers do business with people under 21.  While I’m not a huge fan of people trying to sell me stuff while I’m walking to class, I am incredibly frustrated at how hard this has made it to get a credit card.</p>
<p>Now let’s answer the question as to whether I actually need a credit card.  If the idea behind this law is to prevent young people from making stupid decisions, could I be making one by trying to get a credit card?  People tend to jump to the conclusion that an eighteen year old would only want to use a credit card to buy things that he can’t afford.  I can come up with four other reasons why a credit card is useful that do not involve incurring interest penalties.</p>
<p>1. Credit Building</p>
<p>This was the main motivating factor for me.  While I do not need to borrow money now, my credit report will have a huge impact on the interest rate of any money I borrow in the future.  Additionally, credit reports are used for many things other than borrowing money.  Potential employers and landlords often use this in their decision making process.</p>
<p>2. Insurance/Purchase Protection</p>
<p>Young people buy stuff that can benefit from this too.</p>
<p>3. To help with cash flow</p>
<p>I don’t want to suggest that it is a good thing to regularly rely on credit cards for emergencies.  I like the idea of having an emergency fund.  However, I like to keep mine in an online savings account.  If something comes up that exceeds the amount in my checking account, I can’t just put it on my debit card.  In this situation, having the credit card buys me the two or three days I need for the bank transfer to go through.</p>
<p>4. Cashback</p>
<p>I will admit that at this point my expenses are pretty low, and thus the dollar value of these rewards isn’t very high for me.  However, every place that accepts a credit card has the extra credit card fees built into the price, so it seems silly to throw this away by paying cash.</p>
<p>Now that I’ve established that a young person could want a credit card for responsible reasons, let’s talk about my struggle in getting one.  I didn’t really know where to begin, so I tried to follow what little advice I had.  I had heard it is easier to get approved for a card from a bank you have an account with.  So I applied (the particular bank doesn’t matter, because it’s the same situation across the board because of government regulation).  I got denied immediately, and a week later received a letter in the mail detailing why I had been denied.  Of course the letter listed the obvious reasons: length of accounts and number of accounts.  However, what got my attention was that they listed my credit score, which was in the high 700s.  To explain this I’ll have to give a few more details about my situation.  Before I went to college, my dad added me as an authorized user to one of his credit cards.  He gave me the card and I use it for things we have arranged ahead of time.  After getting my credit report for free online, I determined that the payments for this card were showing up on my credit report.  It should also be noted that the account opened date was before I was born, so that’s interesting.  The only other thing listed on my credit report was the inquiries I had made for several cards.</p>
<p>This is the thing that makes finding cards to apply for very difficult.  Every search tool out there bases what credit cards you should be eligible for one your credit score.  With a high 700’s, the tools claim I am eligible for almost anything, but when I apply to what are supposedly the easiest to get, I am denied.  This means that credit card companies are taking something else into account when they deny me.  I speculate that it could be one of two things.  One could be that they have other criteria for whether someone is approved.  Another might be that they don’t want to deal with the government regulations regarding giving credit cards to young people.</p>
<p>So what did I do about this?  Well, it was clearly that I couldn’t get any unsecured credit cards.  One of my banks actually suggested that I get their secured card.  I liked the idea, but their card charged an annual fee.  So I looked elsewhere.  I decided to get a Discover It Secured Card.  Before you go and sign up, make sure that you get some kind of bonus for doing this.  I unfortunately missed out on this.  Through their referral program, both people get $50, which ultimately gets doubled due to the first year double cashback bonus.  You can either find a friend who has a card and you would like to help out, or you can use my link: <a href="https://refer.discover.com/s/n4bmp">https://refer.discover.com/s/n4bmp</a>. The main reason why I chose the Discover card is because it does not charge an annual fee, and it can graduate to an unsecured card.  You also get some amount of cashback, although it isn’t as good as some of Discover’s other cards.  You also get to set the amount you put as deposit.  When deciding how much to put down, I had two theories in mind.  One was that the amount of I put down for the deposit would be how much I got as unsecured when the card graduated, so I wanted to put as much as possible.  On the other hand, I didn’t want to put too much and delay them from graduating my card because it was too risky.  I still don&#8217;t know for sure whether this card will graduate in a reasonable amount of time.</p>
<p>I’m sorry that I don’t have a solution.  It seems like this is one of those things that isn’t going to change any time soon.  It is incredibly frustrating to be told you’re an adult, but there are going to be a few exceptions until you get past 25.  Let me know how you feel in the comments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>More coming soon&#8230;</title>
		<link>./../2017/09/10/more-coming-soon/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 15:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=276</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve spent a few months hiding from my website, but I think it&#8217;s time to come back and get to work.  What I write is [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve spent a few months hiding from my website, but I think it&#8217;s time to come back and get to work.  What I write is going to stay the same.  I will write things that I think need to be on the internet.  I will not write filler content just to stay on a schedule.</p>
<p>As for my personal life, I spent the summer with my family, as well as camping and hiking.  Here&#8217;s my brother and me at Zion National Park:</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-277" src="https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=860%2C574" alt="" width="860" height="574" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=1024%2C683 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=300%2C200 300w, https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?resize=768%2C512 768w, https://i2.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/NeilEthanZion.jpg?w=1720 1720w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bringing a Gaming PC to College?</title>
		<link>./../2017/02/20/bringing-a-gaming-pc-to-college/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 19:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bringing a gaming pc to school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college pc build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[custom built PC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop pc college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop pc uni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop pc university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming PC at College?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc dorm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc dorm room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc uni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=258</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I made a video discussing five things you should consider when choosing whether or not to bring a gaming PC to college.  Most of these [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made a video discussing five things you should consider when choosing whether or not to bring a gaming PC to college.  Most of these will also apply to any high performance PC.  I&#8217;m not really a gamer, but I did have a computer at home for video editing.  Hopefully this is helpful to you in making your decision.  Enjoy.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IOyP5QReB1U" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Free Premiere Replacement? &#8211; DaVinci Resolve</title>
		<link>./../2017/02/13/a-free-premiere-replacement-davinci-resolve/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 19:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe Premiere Free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advanced Color Correction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackmagic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackmagic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color Correction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color Correction Tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color Grading Tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davinci Resolve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCP Free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCP Replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCP X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Final Cut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Editor Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free NLE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Video Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Video Editor Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Premiere Replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Replacing Premiere]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I released a new video today where I discussed what factors Premiere editors should consider when deciding if they can replace Premiere with DaVinci Resolve.  [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I released a new video today where I discussed what factors Premiere editors should consider when deciding if they can replace Premiere with DaVinci Resolve.  Over the course of editing this video, I actually found solutions to a few of my complains and ended up cutting those parts out.   After gaining more experience using this tool, perhaps I&#8217;ll make a video exploring the software in more detail.  Enjoy.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oTPKrzMDQKE" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moto X Pure Edition (2015) Review</title>
		<link>./../2017/02/06/moto-x-pure-edition-2015-review/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 22:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 6 Marshmallow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android M]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android N]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CM13]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CyanogenMod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Pure Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Pure Edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Stlye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pure Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unlock bootloader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Due to a recent failure of my LG G4, I had to quickly search for a new phone.  Whether or not it&#8217;s the best phone [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Due to a recent failure of my LG G4, I had to quickly search for a new phone.  Whether or not it&#8217;s the best phone for me, I&#8217;ve landed with the Moto X Pure Edition.  It&#8217;s fits what I needed better than most Android phones, but I would&#8217;ve preferred that my G4 keep working.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s my YouTube video where I discuss the important aspects of the phone in more detail:<br />
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ajPYrBTUrU4" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>As always, I appreciate suggestions for anything you&#8217;d like to see me write or make a video about.  You can use the YouTube comments, or the comments on this page.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Problem With The Razer Blade</title>
		<link>./../2017/01/19/my-problem-with-the-razer-blade/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 22:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming Laptop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laptop Battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lenovo T460p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook Killer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Betty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Blade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Blade Battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Blade Reliability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[User Replaceable Laptop Battery]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As much as I like technology, everything I touch seems to develop some kind of problem.  My laptop, the Razer Blade, is not exempt from [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As much as I like technology, everything I touch seems to develop some kind of problem.  My laptop, the Razer Blade, is not exempt from this curse.  I’m not writing this article to bash Razer as a company.  I just want you to know some details that professional reviewers aren’t talking about when they review laptops.</p>
<p>First, the Razer Blade is an impressive computer.  I have the 2013 model, which I got in 2014 when they were selling them at a discount to clear inventory for the new model.  That means I’ve owned this computer for nearly three years now, although I’ve only started using it regularly within the last year.  When the Blade first came out there wasn’t another company making a computer like it.  It has absurd performance, yet still has a compact shell.  When I got this computer I remember noting that it was thinner than the MacBook Pro, the only computer that came close.  Plus, Apple only made a 13” and a 15” and I was looking for a 14”.</p>
<p>This isn’t the first computer Razer ever made.  Razer previously made another laptop that was 17”.  I don’t remember what it was called, and Razer hadn’t been making it that long anyway.  With it being known that Razer had been making computers for no longer than a year or two, I expected that this computer would have some faults, and it did.  However, I was willing to accept a few minor annoyances because there was no other laptop like it.</p>
<p>One of the problems was with the charger.  When the charger was under heavy load, for example, running the computer and charging it at the same time, it would make noise.  To be specific, it was a high pitched whine.  I tossed the charger under the desk, and it wasn’t loud enough to bother me.</p>
<p>Later on I discovered another problem.  During certain weather conditions, one of the fans would come into contact with the bottom of the case.  If this happened all the time, the computer would be going back under warranty for sure, but it happened just infrequently enough that I wasn’t sure they would do anything about it.</p>
<p>While these problems were annoying, they were minor, and didn’t affect the operation of the computer.  Later though, there was a problem with a major component of the laptop, the battery.  The battery life was never great.  If I recall correctly, it is only a 6000mah battery anyway.  That’s barely enough to run my phone all day under heavy use.  The problem comes about when the battery starts to deteriorate.  All batteries do this, and it shouldn’t be a huge cause for concern.  However, the battery life is not just shortened, there is no accurate indication of when the battery is going to die.  The windows feature that puts the computer into hibernate when the battery is low does not function because the battery cannot accurately report its percentage remaining.</p>
<p>I always assumed that when this happened, I’d go online and buy a new one.  I assumed it would be around $50 and easy to find, just like any other device with a battery ever.  This was not the case.  The problem is, the Razer Blade is not a very common computer.  There aren’t any third party manufacturers for the battery.  To make it even worse, Razer does not sell a replacement battery.  The only option is to send it to them for repair for several hundred dollars.  While the computer should be worth in excess of that, I’d have a hard time selling it to anyone else with the problems I mentioned earlier.</p>
<p>For $50 I would replace the battery.  However, several hundred dollars isn’t worth it to me when the battery didn’t even last more than an hour or two to begin with.  After working off the battery and losing my work one time already, I’ve made it a point to never go anywhere without the power adapter.</p>
<p>In the end it comes down to how long you plan on keeping the computer.  If you plan to upgrade every year or every other year, you might not need to consider these long term reliability problems.  I’m sure Razer has resolved their manufacturing faults from the early models, so you shouldn’t worry about that.  However, until a more advanced battery technology is available, the battery will remain a consumable component.  If you can’t replace the battery yourself, the product can only live as long as the battery does.  After that you’ll need to plugged in at all times.</p>
<p>Once I can’t take it anymore, I’ll be searching for a new laptop.  A removable battery will be at the top of my list.  For specs similar to the Razer Blade, I’m looking at Lenovo’s T460p, or perhaps a newer model in that series.  At the moment I primarily use my computer at my desk, and the battery isn’t a huge issue.  My current plan is to wait as long as possible so that my new laptop will be both as new and as cheap as possible.  If this has anything in common with my other technology mishaps, I’ll probably have a new laptop by the end of the year.  If that does happen, I’ll be sure to do a review.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wUox_zqxdng" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Photos from Australia</title>
		<link>./../2017/01/18/photos-from-australia/index.html</link>
		<comments>./../2017/01/18/photos-from-australia/index.html#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 22:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boroka Lookout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canberra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grampians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grampians National Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Halls Gap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kangaroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacKenzie Falls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melbourne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NSW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Observatory Hill Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parliament House]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sydney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sydney Harbour Bride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taronga Zoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victoria]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=227</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In case you&#8217;re one of the last people who hasn&#8217;t found out yet, I spent my &#8220;winter&#8221; break in Australia.  The good news was it [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In case you&#8217;re one of the last people who hasn&#8217;t found out yet, I spent my &#8220;winter&#8221; break in Australia.  The good news was it was actually summer, and the weather was quite nice.  I enjoyed my time there, and I have good friends to thank for that.  I&#8217;m not a huge fan of sharing my personal vacation photos on the internet, nor do I think many people would be interested in them.  However, I thought it would be good to share the photos that I uploaded to 500px, and talk a little bit more about how I shot them, and what I was thinking at the time.  All photos will have the context below the photo it refers to.</p>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382665/m%3D900/691bf089223443caad14cf0352612856" alt="Opera House at Night by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>I would consider this photo one of my favorites.  I&#8217;ve even set it as my desktop background.  This is a long exposure, although if I were to take it again I think I&#8217;d try to get a longer exposure.  This one was only 15 seconds.  Unfortunately the only camera I have anymore is a Micro 4/3, which isn&#8217;t nearly as good at low light as the Canon cameras I used to have.</p>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382685/m%3D900/f568682a17f6d0985b65cec47bda97f6" alt="Harbour Bridge at Night by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
</div>
<p>This is another photo I took the same night.  If this isn&#8217;t a landmark you recognize, the subject is the Sydney Harbour Bridge.  This one was handheld, and I used my 20mm pancake lens.  I am impressed with nearly every photo I take will this lens.  The dots you see above the bridge are birds, and unfortunately not stars.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382663/m%3D900/3338444eb242079e0df3f44952a637b8" alt="Flags by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>For whatever reason I really enjoy taking pictures of flags.  They are a challenge to capture, but not nearly as difficult to capture as animals.  In this photo they&#8217;ve caught the wind quite well, and are flying in the optimal direction.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382661/m%3D900/8b09a097e364c7eed5fe9e5d684bb125" alt="Sydney Harbour by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>This one was challenging to edit the exposure on, and I&#8217;m still not entirely sure that I have it how I like it.  I think this photo really benefited from the polarizer filter that I used.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382701/m%3D900/3a8129319d0bc4d12fc9644e928af6ed" alt="Not Paris by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>This one is on the Harbour Bridge.  Someone has tried to start something like they have in Paris, and a few others have played along.  The framed the Opera House nicely from my perspective.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382703/m%3D900/3d8f40bad839c52a34674b4184985b8f" alt="Harbour Bridge by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>Probably one of my favorite spots that I visited in Sydney was the Observatory Hill Park.  Walking around you could get a nice view in most directions, including of the Harbour Bridge.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382631/m%3D900/5e3ae8400d24aaa80475adba64274ad2" alt="What" /></p>
<p>This one would be interesting for some sort of contest where you have to guess where in the world this is.  It should be pretty easy to identify, but perhaps the viewer doesn&#8217;t look where I&#8217;m looking.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382633/m%3D900/9855ea3aed1d1f18717d84881c262d90" alt="Wallaby by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>This one is from Taronga Zoo in Sydney.  I&#8217;m not that great at photographing animals, but this one managed to turn out alright.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382681/m%3D900/bbd7e4f742dc1a4f816b0ce8815ebe28" alt="Parilament House by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>This photo was taken on the roof of Parliament House is Canberra.  Yes, they will let pretty much anyone on the roof.</p>
</div>
<div class="pixels-photo">
<p><img src="https://drscdn.500px.org/photo/193382683/m%3D900/1dc370870ae5a5e0f5441bdfa9268109" alt="Boroka Lookout by Neil Wilcoxson on 500px.com" /></p>
<p>This is Boroka Lookout near Halls Gap in Victoria.  It&#8217;s a good view, and from one of the days I enjoyed most on my trip.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-230" src="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg?resize=860%2C574" alt="" width="860" height="574" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg?resize=1024%2C683 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg?resize=300%2C200 300w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg?resize=768%2C512 768w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/P1020734edit.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>I went ahead and threw in one of my personal photos anyway.  This is at MacKenzie Falls, also near Halls Gap.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>./../2017/01/18/photos-from-australia/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qantas Flight 7/8 &#8211; Sydney &#038; Dallas</title>
		<link>./../2017/01/15/qantas-flight-78-sydney-dallas/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 20:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A380]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A380 economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A380 economy cabin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbus A380]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airplane food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aisle seat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america to australia flight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inflight entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international flight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long haul flight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle seat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qantas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qantas aisle seat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qantas economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qantas inflight entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QF7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[QF8]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../index.html?p=205</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don’t really want to call myself a travel blogger.  However, I thought it would be useful to have some information about this flight out [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don’t really want to call myself a travel blogger.  However, I thought it would be useful to have some information about this flight out there.  The existing information isn’t bad, but there are a few aspects that I couldn’t find as many details about as I would have liked to.</p>
<h3>Flight Details</h3>
<p>Qantas Flights 7 and 8 are always Dallas/Fort Worth (DFW) to Sydney (SYD).  At the time of this writing they are operated on the Airbus A380.  This flight is very long.  The flight to Sydney takes just over 17 hours, and the flight to Dallas comes in at just under 16.</p>
<h3>Scheduling Concerns</h3>
<p>One thing that worries me about this flight is that there is only one per day.  That means if you are doing anything other than using it as a nonstop flight, you risk having to wait a whole day if your connection is late.  I was arriving directly to DFW on the way out, so this was not a problem on that end.  However, on my return, I had a connecting flight from Melbourne to Sydney, which ended up being delayed.  The problem was I only had one hour and ten minutes to make the connection.  What I wasn’t fully aware of is that at Sydney airport, you are transferred by bus between the domestic and international terminals, which takes time.  You must exit through customs, which takes time.  You must go through a stricter security checkpoint, which takes time.  The “good” news was that the Dallas flight was also delayed, giving me just enough time to make it.  Although everything worked out in the end, I probably wouldn’t try to do the same thing again.</p>
<p>Another scheduling thing to remember is that Sydney Airport has a curfew, meaning that no flights can land before 6AM.  According to our captain, although we arrived in the area around 5:30, we still had to que behind several other aircraft, making our arrival into the airport more like 6:30, rather than the scheduled 6:05.  I didn’t have anywhere to be, so I didn’t mind, but this could be frustrating if you were trying to make a connection.  Also, flight times change based on the season, so if your flight isn’t set to arrive at 6:05, this shouldn’t be as much of a problem.</p>
<h3>Food</h3>
<p>I know that people like to complain about airplane food.  The complaints that people generally have about it also applies to the food on this flight.  I didn’t really have a problem with it, but I wouldn’t want to have to eat it all the time either.  Here are some photos for reference:</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-214" src="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg?resize=860%2C645" alt="" width="860" height="645" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg?resize=1024%2C768 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasDinner.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>Above is the tortellini.  Below is the scrambled eggs.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-216" src="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg?resize=860%2C645" alt="" width="860" height="645" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg?resize=1024%2C768 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBreakfast.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>What I do have a problem with is their menu.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-209" src="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg?resize=860%2C645" alt="" width="860" height="645" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg?resize=1024%2C768 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasBothMenu.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>My problem with their menu is that it uses really big words that I don’t know how to pronounce.  I can roughly determine what the food I’ll be getting is, but I didn’t appreciate how stupid I felt trying to tell the flight attendant which of the three meals I would like.  I much prefer the ANA way where they assume no one speaks their language, and bring out very accurate pictures of what the food is, and ask you to point to the one you want.</p>
<p>Another aspect of the food is the snacks.  I was happy with the frequency at which I was offered them.  The snacks offered on the way to Australia were merely adequate.  I enjoyed the snacks offered on the way to the US much more.  In particular, I enjoyed the platter of prepackaged snacks that they brought around and allowed you to pick whatever you would like.  This consisted mostly of things made in Australia, and that are hard to find elsewhere.</p>
<h3>Entertainment</h3>
<p>The inflight entertainment system in Qantas’ A380s is on the older side.  There is a USB Port available (on the front of the armrest), but I think it was originally intended for media playback, and not for charging your phone.  My phone took around five hours to charge.  I imagine it is only capable of supplying 500mA, so if you have an iPhone, it would probably refuse to change.  I believe there are also A/C ports available, but I didn’t need to use it, and didn’t happen to locate it by chance.</p>
<p>Perhaps more important is the selection of content that they have available.  At the time of my flight they had plenty of movies available.  However, I’m more interested in TV Shows, of which they also had quite a few.  The thing that was particularly interesting is that they didn’t just have one or two episodes of each show, they had entire seasons.  This made it easier to stay entertained once you found a show that you liked.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-215" src="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg?resize=860%2C645" alt="" width="860" height="645" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg?resize=1024%2C768 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i1.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/QantasFlightMap.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>Something else I liked taking a look at was the flight map and the tail camera.  The flight map is ridiculously detailed at times, to the point where I was able to determine exactly which coastal city we were flying over in California.  Unfortunately, the tail camera is very low resolution, and you aren’t going to see much apart from takeoff and landing.  Also, it took longer than expected to load, leaving me wondering whether it was broken.</p>
<h3>Seating Arrangement</h3>
<p>The seating arrangement on Qantas’ A380s is the best they could do with what they had.  The outer sections are three seats wide, and the middle section is four seats wide.  My personal preference for flights of this duration is to sit in an aisle seat of the middle section.  The main thing I accomplish by picking one of these seats is being able to stand up whenever I’d like.  Also, I have less of a chance of having to stand up to let someone out.  In theory, people don’t book middle seats in the middle section unless they want to sit next to someone they’re traveling with.  In which case they are more likely to ask that person to stand up than to ask me.  I was lucky enough to have an empty seat next to me on one of my flights.  On the flight back I wasn’t as lucky, but fortunately people who choose these seats often sleep most of the time.</p>
<h3>The Toilets</h3>
<p>You wouldn’t think there would be much to say about airplane toilets.  The truth is, there are only the slightest bit larger than other aircraft I’ve been on.  The toilets themselves do their job and I don’t have any complaints about that.  The only thing worth mentioning is that there were always people waiting to use them.  It could be the type of people that are taking this flight at this time of year (there did seem to be a lot of families), because it seems like the number of toilets was sufficient.  Also, don’t bother trying to use the toilet during the two hours or so before landing.  People seem to take much longer during this time, probably in an attempt to take a shower or something.</p>
<h3>The Small Plane Effect</h3>
<p>To be honest, I was expecting the world’s largest passenger aircraft to feel a lot larger.  I thought that every once and a while I’d get up on walk the length of the plane and maybe even go upstairs.  This did not happen.  I’m not sure if you are actually prohibited from doing this, but the way the plane is setup certainly implies that you shouldn’t.  Even within economy, there are several sections which get divided by curtains after takeoff.</p>
<h3>Jetlag</h3>
<p>Of course jetlag will have a different effect on different people, but I’ll share some details that might help you determine how you will be affected.  First, the flight to Sydney departs at night and arrives in the morning.  Chances are you won’t be able to just arrive and go to sleep.  Knowing this, I tried to sleep on the flight, which got me around an hour of sleep.  Also, depending on the type of accommodation you’ve booked, you may also have trouble finding a place to store your luggage.  Going in the other direction, there shouldn’t be as many problems.  First of all, the flight is slightly shorter, but also, it arrives at a more manageable time of day, the early afternoon.  I can’t comment in as much detail on the challenges associated with this direction because I live on this side and just drove my personal car.</p>
<p>These are the main things I noticed about this flight.  If you have more questions about this flight, you can comment below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
