<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Technology &#8211; Neil Wilcoxson</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>CS Student and non-Professional Photographer</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 19:39:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>When will Bitcoin become less volatile?</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/11/05/when-will-bitcoin-become-less-volatile/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 16:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deflation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dollars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiat currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government currency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inflation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investor confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetary policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetary sytem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speculation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volatile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volatility]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The exchange rate for Bitcoin has been all over the place over the past few months, going as high as $7500 recently, and as low [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The exchange rate for Bitcoin has been all over the place over the past few months, going as high as $7500 recently, and as low as $3000 in September.  These price fluctuations are caused by speculation.  By speculation, I mean that people are buying it simply hoping that they will buy it now and then sell it later for a higher price.  I haven&#8217;t heard of many people exchanging their money for Bitcoin because it was necessary to go and buy some product or service that they wanted.  This leads to a circular problem.  Merchants don&#8217;t want to accept Bitcoin because it is so volatile.  On the other side of the coin, Bitcoin is volatile because most of its trading activity is done by people who are speculating on it.</p>
<p>There is a way to solve for this, but the first people to attempt it will see it as a huge risk.  The problem with Bitcoin is that merchants who accept want to charge the amount of Bitcoin that is precisely equivalent, at the time of the transaction, to the amount they would charge for the same item in dollars.  If someone wanted to use Bitcoin as their daily currency, a daily cup of coffee (or other item purchased regularly) would change in price everyday, by a lot.  Yes, some products, like gasoline, change in price on a daily basis, but not nearly to the extent that the Bitcoin exchange rate does.  Bitcoin will become much more viable when there are businesses that set a price in Bitcoin, not in the local government currency.  Ultimately this means that a business has to only accept Bitcoin, because if they offered both forms of payment, people would pick the one worth less at the time of the transaction.</p>
<p>Businesses take a loss when they decide to exchange their Bitcoin immediately at the time of the transaction.  However, this is necessary to cover expenses that must be paid in the government currency.  Perhaps taxes will always be paid in the government&#8217;s currency, but that doesn&#8217;t mean everything else has to be.  It would be difficult for a business to pay everyone else in Bitcoin.  If a business requires material goods, the others businesses providing those must be willing the accept Bitcoin.  Furthermore, employees have to be willing to accept Bitcoin.  For the employees to be willing to accept it, other businesses have to accept it.  Thus the cycle continues.</p>
<p>People are comfortable with dollars because they are confident that the paycheck they earn today will buy them the food they need tomorrow, the same way it did last week, and the weeks before that.  If we stopped comparing Bitcoin to the dollar, Bitcoin would also be able to provide this comfort.  In other words, Bitcoin will become less volatile when we start thinking about its value in terms of the goods and services it can buy, rather than how much of the government&#8217;s currency it can buy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will the Moto X (2015) Ever Get Updated?</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/10/29/will-the-moto-x-2015-ever-get-updated/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 13:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 6.0 Marshmallow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 7.0 Nougat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android security updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bootloader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lineage OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Pure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola bootloader unlock code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nexus 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ROM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TWRP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[updating Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warranty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have a Moto X Pure Edition which I bought at the end of last year as a last minute replacement to my LG G4, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a Moto X Pure Edition which I bought at the end of last year as a last minute replacement to my LG G4, which was poorly manufactured, and conveniently just out of warranty. Of the phones that were available to buy that day in Best Buy, the Moto X was the best option, but not necessarily a great option.</p>
<p>In my mind, Motorola had a reputation for keeping their phones up to date.  I had also heard that they made it easy to unlock your bootloader, even providing official instructions on how to do it.  Well, once you own one of their phones, your view on those things changes.  When I took the phone out of the box, it was on Android 5 Lollipop, but there was an update waiting, and I did that.  Now the phone was on Android 6 Marshmallow.  People kept posting online saying that the update to Android 7 Nougat was just around the corner.  To this day, that update has never arrived officially from Motorola.  And worse than that, the security patches are only up to December 2016.</p>
<p>Thinking that the update was just around the corner, I avoided unlocking the bootloader and installing Lineage OS (the replacement for CyanogenMod, which has had Android 7 available on the Moto X for a while now).  I would have just done it, but Motorola has a catch to providing the bootloader unlock code that people don&#8217;t tell you about, it voids the warranty.  Not just in the sense that they won&#8217;t fix anything stupid you do to the software under warranty, obtaining the code literally puts you in a database for no warranty work.  Given my bad experience with the LG G4 which failed by way of the same chipset that was in the Moto X, I wanted the warranty in force for as long as possible.  But recent Android security concerns changed my stance on this.  I went and got the unlock code and installed Lineage OS.  Even though they don&#8217;t offer a stable build yet, I&#8217;ve found it to have less bugs than the software that Motorola provided.</p>
<p>But wait, there&#8217;s more.  Whenever I start up the phone, it displays an obnoxious message about the bootloader being unlocked.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-315" src="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=860%2C574" alt="" width="860" height="574" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=1024%2C683 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=300%2C200 300w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?resize=768%2C512 768w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?w=1720 1720w, https://i0.wp.com/neilwilcoxson.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/MotoXNexusBootComp.jpg?w=2580 2580w" sizes="(max-width: 860px) 100vw, 860px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a></p>
<p>On the right is my Nexus 5 with a tasteful warning that the bootloader has been unlocked.  On the left is my Moto X telling you that using this device might injure people.  There is a way to replace this message with something else, but I think I&#8217;ll just leave it so I can have a good laugh at the expense of Motorola every time I restart my phone.</p>
<p>So the answer to the question: Will the Moto X ever get updated?  Officially no, but you can make it happen if you&#8217;re out of warranty or don&#8217;t mind voiding it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bringing a Gaming PC to College?</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/02/20/bringing-a-gaming-pc-to-college/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 19:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bringing a gaming pc to school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college pc build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[custom built PC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop pc college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop pc uni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop pc university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming PC at College?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc dorm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc dorm room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc uni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming pc university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=258</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I made a video discussing five things you should consider when choosing whether or not to bring a gaming PC to college.  Most of these [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made a video discussing five things you should consider when choosing whether or not to bring a gaming PC to college.  Most of these will also apply to any high performance PC.  I&#8217;m not really a gamer, but I did have a computer at home for video editing.  Hopefully this is helpful to you in making your decision.  Enjoy.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IOyP5QReB1U" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Free Premiere Replacement? &#8211; DaVinci Resolve</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/02/13/a-free-premiere-replacement-davinci-resolve/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 19:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adobe Premiere Free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advanced Color Correction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackmagic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackmagic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color Correction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color Correction Tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color Grading Tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Davinci Resolve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCP Free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCP Replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FCP X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Final Cut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Editor Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free NLE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Video Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free Video Editor Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Premiere Replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Replacing Premiere]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I released a new video today where I discussed what factors Premiere editors should consider when deciding if they can replace Premiere with DaVinci Resolve.  [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I released a new video today where I discussed what factors Premiere editors should consider when deciding if they can replace Premiere with DaVinci Resolve.  Over the course of editing this video, I actually found solutions to a few of my complains and ended up cutting those parts out.   After gaining more experience using this tool, perhaps I&#8217;ll make a video exploring the software in more detail.  Enjoy.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oTPKrzMDQKE" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moto X Pure Edition (2015) Review</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/02/06/moto-x-pure-edition-2015-review/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 22:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 6 Marshmallow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android M]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android N]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CM13]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CyanogenMod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lenovo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Pure Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Pure Edition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X Stlye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pure Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unlock bootloader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Due to a recent failure of my LG G4, I had to quickly search for a new phone.  Whether or not it&#8217;s the best phone [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Due to a recent failure of my LG G4, I had to quickly search for a new phone.  Whether or not it&#8217;s the best phone for me, I&#8217;ve landed with the Moto X Pure Edition.  It&#8217;s fits what I needed better than most Android phones, but I would&#8217;ve preferred that my G4 keep working.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s my YouTube video where I discuss the important aspects of the phone in more detail:<br />
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ajPYrBTUrU4" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>As always, I appreciate suggestions for anything you&#8217;d like to see me write or make a video about.  You can use the YouTube comments, or the comments on this page.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Problem With The Razer Blade</title>
		<link>./../../../2017/01/19/my-problem-with-the-razer-blade/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 22:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming Laptop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laptop Battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lenovo T460p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MacBook Killer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Betty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Blade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Blade Battery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Razer Blade Reliability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[User Replaceable Laptop Battery]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As much as I like technology, everything I touch seems to develop some kind of problem.  My laptop, the Razer Blade, is not exempt from [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As much as I like technology, everything I touch seems to develop some kind of problem.  My laptop, the Razer Blade, is not exempt from this curse.  I’m not writing this article to bash Razer as a company.  I just want you to know some details that professional reviewers aren’t talking about when they review laptops.</p>
<p>First, the Razer Blade is an impressive computer.  I have the 2013 model, which I got in 2014 when they were selling them at a discount to clear inventory for the new model.  That means I’ve owned this computer for nearly three years now, although I’ve only started using it regularly within the last year.  When the Blade first came out there wasn’t another company making a computer like it.  It has absurd performance, yet still has a compact shell.  When I got this computer I remember noting that it was thinner than the MacBook Pro, the only computer that came close.  Plus, Apple only made a 13” and a 15” and I was looking for a 14”.</p>
<p>This isn’t the first computer Razer ever made.  Razer previously made another laptop that was 17”.  I don’t remember what it was called, and Razer hadn’t been making it that long anyway.  With it being known that Razer had been making computers for no longer than a year or two, I expected that this computer would have some faults, and it did.  However, I was willing to accept a few minor annoyances because there was no other laptop like it.</p>
<p>One of the problems was with the charger.  When the charger was under heavy load, for example, running the computer and charging it at the same time, it would make noise.  To be specific, it was a high pitched whine.  I tossed the charger under the desk, and it wasn’t loud enough to bother me.</p>
<p>Later on I discovered another problem.  During certain weather conditions, one of the fans would come into contact with the bottom of the case.  If this happened all the time, the computer would be going back under warranty for sure, but it happened just infrequently enough that I wasn’t sure they would do anything about it.</p>
<p>While these problems were annoying, they were minor, and didn’t affect the operation of the computer.  Later though, there was a problem with a major component of the laptop, the battery.  The battery life was never great.  If I recall correctly, it is only a 6000mah battery anyway.  That’s barely enough to run my phone all day under heavy use.  The problem comes about when the battery starts to deteriorate.  All batteries do this, and it shouldn’t be a huge cause for concern.  However, the battery life is not just shortened, there is no accurate indication of when the battery is going to die.  The windows feature that puts the computer into hibernate when the battery is low does not function because the battery cannot accurately report its percentage remaining.</p>
<p>I always assumed that when this happened, I’d go online and buy a new one.  I assumed it would be around $50 and easy to find, just like any other device with a battery ever.  This was not the case.  The problem is, the Razer Blade is not a very common computer.  There aren’t any third party manufacturers for the battery.  To make it even worse, Razer does not sell a replacement battery.  The only option is to send it to them for repair for several hundred dollars.  While the computer should be worth in excess of that, I’d have a hard time selling it to anyone else with the problems I mentioned earlier.</p>
<p>For $50 I would replace the battery.  However, several hundred dollars isn’t worth it to me when the battery didn’t even last more than an hour or two to begin with.  After working off the battery and losing my work one time already, I’ve made it a point to never go anywhere without the power adapter.</p>
<p>In the end it comes down to how long you plan on keeping the computer.  If you plan to upgrade every year or every other year, you might not need to consider these long term reliability problems.  I’m sure Razer has resolved their manufacturing faults from the early models, so you shouldn’t worry about that.  However, until a more advanced battery technology is available, the battery will remain a consumable component.  If you can’t replace the battery yourself, the product can only live as long as the battery does.  After that you’ll need to plugged in at all times.</p>
<p>Once I can’t take it anymore, I’ll be searching for a new laptop.  A removable battery will be at the top of my list.  For specs similar to the Razer Blade, I’m looking at Lenovo’s T460p, or perhaps a newer model in that series.  At the moment I primarily use my computer at my desk, and the battery isn’t a huge issue.  My current plan is to wait as long as possible so that my new laptop will be both as new and as cheap as possible.  If this has anything in common with my other technology mishaps, I’ll probably have a new laptop by the end of the year.  If that does happen, I’ll be sure to do a review.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wUox_zqxdng" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UPDATE: LG G4 Replacement</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/12/12/update-lg-g4-replacement/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 02:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android Bootloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android Phone Problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[G4 Replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 Bootloop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 Chipset Problem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G4 Dead]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moto X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola void warranty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motrola Unlock Bootloader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motrola X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unlock bootloader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unlock bootloader Androird]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=197</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Unfortunately I don&#8217;t have time to make a well produced video sharing all of the details of my situation. However, I would like to share [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Unfortunately I don&#8217;t have time to make a well produced video sharing all of the details of my situation. However, I would like to share some details about what has happened lately, because I feel like the video I posted a few weeks ago left the whole thing a little open ended.</p>
<p>First, a refresh about what happened.  I was going about my day as I normally would, and while using it, my phone shut off.  The bootloader screen came up, but got stuck.  I attempted several restarts and got the phone all the way booted several times, but could never stay on for more than five minutes or so.  I thought it was a software problem, and reflashed the ROM, but I had no luck.  Upon further research, I found out that this was happening as a result of a hardware fault, which the internet had known about since the beginning of the year.  Unfortunately, my phone outlasted the one year warranty, and I ended up having to get a new phone.  This is where I left off at the end of the video I posted.  If you&#8217;re interested in seeing me explain it in the moment you can watch the video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zRVwj5TNfBQ">here.</a></p>
<p>Another frustrating aspect to the whole situation is that I had the phone leased on Jump on Demand (through T-Mobile).  I had three months remaining, and then I was planning on paying off the phone and keeping it because I liked it&#8217;s features, as I mentioned in my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_VPeswyxF5Q">Finding a Long Lasting Phone video</a>.  This wasn&#8217;t going to be possible.</p>
<p>The phone I ended getting a Moto X.  I would have liked to get a phone that I could add an extended battery to, but there aren&#8217;t very many of those out there, and at this point they are mostly very low end phones.  Most standard phone batteries cannot make it through the day with my usage, and the Moto X is no exception.  Now I have to work out a mobile charging solution, which is inconvenient, but I can manage.  If it was the case that I couldn&#8217;t get an extended battery, I might have considered a phone from OnePlus, but I needed something I could get quick, and all of the OnePlus phones were backordered at the time.  Ultimately I&#8217;m okay with this selection because the Moto X has pretty much the same specs are the LG G4.  The Moto X also has a purer version of Android, one of my main complaints about the G4.</p>
<p>At some point I&#8217;ll be sure to make a video detailing my impressions.  However, I will be waiting a while, because there are already plenty of videos from people who have used the phone for about a week.  I&#8217;d rather discuss aspects of the phone that will impact the long term.  I&#8217;ll also have to discuss the fact that to get the unlock code for the bootloader, you have to agree to void the warranty, something that I don&#8217;t want to do, considering what happened to my last phone.  So yes, I&#8217;ll be running on non-rooted Android for a while.</p>
<p>In summary, this whole thing sucks, and I would have been perfectly happy keeping my LG G4.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Video Setup Tour (2016)</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/11/13/video-setup-tour-2016/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1080p]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[20mm lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camera gear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DSLR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equipment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HD video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lav mic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Micro 4/3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panasonic GX7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Setup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Setup Tour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube gear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube setup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zoom H1]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=176</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week I&#8217;ve made a quick tour of my video setup. It&#8217;s just about the smallest amount of equipment that I could use to pull [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week I&#8217;ve made a quick tour of my video setup. It&#8217;s just about the smallest amount of equipment that I could use to pull off my current quality. I&#8217;ve put links to my equipment below.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R0zYitD9Z1U" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Gear in this video (affiliate links):<br />
Panasonic Lumix GX7: http://amzn.to/2fJ8mrW<br />
Panasonic 20mm f/1.7: http://amzn.to/2g3r7Lg<br />
Manfrotto 701HDV: http://amzn.to/2fJ9JXN<br />
LED Panel: http://amzn.to/2fXNjXK<br />
Eneloop Power Pack (Batteries): http://amzn.to/2fJ9FYb<br />
Manfrotto MKBFR4A4-BH: http://amzn.to/2fJevo4<br />
Zoom H1 Audio Recorder: http://amzn.to/2eL0p4X<br />
Sony ECMCS3 Lav: http://amzn.to/2fEBTnT<br />
Kindle Fire (2015): http://amzn.to/2fEGE0S<br />
White Balance Card: http://amzn.to/2fJ9FaC<br />
Tenba Discovery Messenger: http://amzn.to/2g3sRnH<br />
Tripod Bag (verify size): http://amzn.to/2fEIL4V<br />
<iframe style="border: none;" src="//rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?o=1&amp;p=12&amp;l=ur1&amp;category=warehouse&amp;banner=0WH1TBABMW4R4HN14382&amp;f=ifr&amp;lc=pf4&amp;linkID=e7c23d72dbee70ebc18568168fd37335&amp;t=nwphotographs-20&amp;tracking_id=nwphotographs-20" width="300" height="250" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Switching to Micro 4/3</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/11/10/switching-to-micro-43/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 19:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camera system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DSLR video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interchangable lens cameras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mirco 4/3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mirco four thirds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portable camera system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[switching from canon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[switching from nikon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[system camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel camera system]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=179</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First, let’s put my opinion in perspective.  The first interchangeable lens camera that I used was a Canon REBEL T1i.  I later upgraded to a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First, let’s put my opinion in perspective.  The first interchangeable lens camera that I used was a Canon REBEL T1i.  I later upgraded to a T4i, mostly for video features.  After deciding that my Canon setup occupied to much space for a trip that I was taking, I decided to look into smaller options.  I went with an older model Micro 4/3 camera, the Panasonic GX7.  I kept both systems around for a while, and used each one when it was appropriate.  However, since I had college just around the corner, I didn’t see myself having time to fully utilize two camera systems.  After a while I realized that the longer I waited to sell one of them, the more it would depreciate, so I elected to sell my Canon system, which I had owned for longer.  I decided that I could always buy a much nicer system once I graduated, and having no leftovers would allow me to make a decision based on which was the best, not based on what gear I already owned.  Having decided to use Micro 4/3 for now, I thought I’d share some Pros and Cons of the system to help you make your decision.</p>
<h2>Pros</h2>
<h3>Smaller equipment size</h3>
<p>This was the primary reason why I chose Micro 4/3.  As I mentioned previous, I take a lot of photos while travelling.  For certain trips, I just couldn’t bring a huge camera system.  With my GX7, I do not need a dedicated camera bag.  I can toss everything I need into whatever bag I’d be carrying anyway.</p>
<h3>Many manufacturers making compatible lenses</h3>
<p>Even though I haven’t made heavy use of this feature, it is worth mentioning.  It will probably be most useful when it comes time to get a new camera body.  I like knowing I can keep my current lenses even if I choose a different manufacturer.</p>
<h3>Lenses from other systems more easily adapted</h3>
<p>This comes down to sensor size.  Any lenses designed for a sensor at or lower than the size of Micro 4/3 can be adapted with a passive adapter.  This is quite popular, and many adapters are available for cheap.  I don’t have any experience with these other than being aware of their existence.</p>
<h3>Good for video</h3>
<p>Even if still photo quality can’t quite match bigger sensors, video is lower resolution, and the difference isn’t as noticeable.  I now shoot most of my YouTube videos with my GX7, and in most cases the quality is the same or better than the Canon system I used before.  There are also more video oriented cameras like the GH4.  Some Blackmagic cameras (which are dedicated to video) also use Micro 4/3 lenses.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The smaller sensor also has a deeper depth of field.  This refers to the range of distances from the lens that are in focus.  This does make it harder to get blurry backgrounds, but it makes the camera’s autofocus more reliable.  Depending on the situation, I can actually use it for video, whereas Canon’s system was never good enough for my tastes.</p>
<h3>Less professional looking</h3>
<p>Especially when you’re traveling in unfamiliar places, the last thing you want is to stick out.  When you use a camera with the DSLR body style, people automatically associate it with what the pros use, and assume it is expensive.  My GX7 (especially with smaller lenses attached) makes people think I’m holding an older point and shoot.</p>
<h2>Cons</h2>
<h3>Low light performance</h3>
<p>This is the biggest drawback for me.  When shooting on my Canon system, I discovered that ISOs of up to 1600 would look clean, and 3200 would be okay depending on the situation.  This is not the case with Micro 4/3.  Of course, technology is getting better all the time, but with my GX7, the highest I really want to go is ISO 800.  Beyond that, noise starts getting introduced to the image.</p>
<h3>Less professional looking</h3>
<p>I know I previously said that this can be a pro, but it can also be a con.  If someone is paying you to be a photographer, you don’t want them thinking you’re using cheap equipment.  Of course, you and I know that Micro 4/3 systems aren’t cheap, but they’re just going off looks.  This also depends a lot on the camera you’re using.  A GH4 has a pretty large body and shouldn’t cause many problems.</p>
<h3>More expensive</h3>
<p>Even though I bought an older model camera, it still didn’t come cheap.  To get my GX7, a 14-140 zoom, and 20mm prime, I paid nearly $2000.  Prices change all the time, so I can’t say exactly what you’ll pay, but be prepared to pay more for camera bodies and lenses.  If you’re up for experimentation, you can consider adapting older lenses, which can be found cheap online.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hopefully my experience has helped.  Let me know if there’s any more information I can provide that would be helpful.  I’ll consider making a YouTube video on this topic if there is enough demand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mass Data Storage: My Solution</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/11/07/mass-data-storage-my-solution/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 23:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Neil]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Backup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code 42]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crashplan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drobo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hard Drive Toaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hard Drives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HDD Toaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laptop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mass Data Storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Backup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RAID]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SSDs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USB 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USB 3.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=174</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve uploaded a new video on YouTube. This week I&#8217;ll talk about my solution for storing video and other large files. It&#8217;s more of a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve uploaded a new video on YouTube. This week I&#8217;ll talk about my solution for storing video and other large files. It&#8217;s more of a story, but hopefully you&#8217;ll be able to find some ideas to improve your system.  Watch below:<br />
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JM_rAqEjPZA" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an affiliate link for the &#8220;Hard Drive Toaster&#8221;: <a href="http://amzn.to/2eGVEfT">http://amzn.to/2eGVEfT</a></p>
<p>and Hard Drive Cases: <a href="http://amzn.to/2eGWd9v">http://amzn.to/2eGWd9v</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
